# Junior Level Developer/Designer

Over 8 years of experience working in a large corporate environment. Able to coordinate with other highly skilled professionals to facilitate completion of projects. Self-starter, driven to produce high quality, consistent results. Prioritize and manage work flow of large and small scale requests simultaneously to ensure deadlines are met. Life-long learner with excellent project management, design, and technical skill set. Graduate of the 9 week Microsoft .Net Accelerated Learning Program at Eleven Fifty Academy, located in Carmel and Fishers, IN. Former Design Specialist with Steelcase furniture dealership, onsite at Eli Lilly, transitioning into development.

- Application development with C# and Visual Studio
- Familiarity with both front end and back end design
- Experience in web design with HTML, CSS, and Javascript, using Sublime Text
- Utilization of Git version control system
- Excellent work ethic and highly attentive to detail
- Adept at working independently and on a team
- Highly proficient at translating client wants/needs into a viable solution
- Knowledge of Microsoft Office suite: Outlook, Word, Excel, PowerPoint
- Highly analytical mindset and strong problem solving skills
- Skilled at creating customized solutions and developing repeatable processes
- Exceptional organizational skills, as well as written and verbal communication skills

### **EXPERIENCE**

## Eleven Fifty Academy Carmel, IN

.NET Apprentice, September 2016 to present

Eleven Fifty Academy's Apprenticeship program serves as a bridge between the classroom and employment. It is an opportunity to practice and continue to learn about the industry.

- Introduced to Confluence and JIRA
- o Currently working on group based Shopping List app in C# and Visual Studio
- Serving as configuration manager for group's Git repository

## Eleven Fifty Academy Carmel, IN

.NET Accelerated Learning Program Student, June 2016 to August 2016

As a 9-week course, Eleven Fifty Academy's Accelerated Learning Program trains students in programming fundamentals, while utilizing real world scenarios and providing a well-rounded curriculum.

- Developed several MVC applications in C# and Visual Studio
- Setup and updated SQL Server databases for applications as needed, using Entity Framework and Code First Migrations

260.402.8726

- Deployed applications using Microsoft Azure and assisted classmates with the deployment process
- o Customized front end and/or back end design for all applications
- o Familiarized with debugging applications and basic unit testing
- o Created a professional portfolio website, using HTML, CSS, and JavaScript in Sublime Text
- o Introduced to cross-platform mobile application using Xamarin
- o Setup and utilized Git for version control
- Formally trained in Agile methodology and Scrum
- Participated in additional courses, including Professional Etiquette, Testing, Security, UX/UI Design, Deployment, etc.

#### Business Furniture LLC Indianapolis, IN

Design Team Lead, Onsite at Eli Lilly, February 2016 to June 2016

- Conducted weekly meetings to ensure consistency and to maintain standards
- Mentored design staff regarding process and project specifics
- o Facilitated communication between Business Furniture and design team

## Design Specialist, Onsite at Eli Lilly, September 2007 to June 2016

- Completed over 100 requests per year successfully, with installations ranging from a single station to 130 stations
- Regularly redesigned existing product in new configurations
- Blended existing product with new standards to enhance spaces
- Followed iterative design process throughout, with focus on customer approval prior to proceeding with installation
- Documented project process throughout for reference and audits
- Assigned to work with high level clients and executives
- Acted as project coordinator, product owner, and designer daily
- Managed and prioritized multiple projects and smaller requests simultaneously
- Engaged directly with customers to evaluate needs and requirements
- Provided excellent communication throughout the design process, including e-mail correspondence, updates, and follow up
- Explained details and processes to customers and vendors as needed and established rapport
- o Engaged other crews and vendors when required to satisfy customer needs
- Managed the artwork inventory onsite and maintained database and spreadsheets
- Developed and modified processes to address a variety of large scale artwork, branding, and signage projects.

#### Ethan Allen Interiors Indianapolis, IN

Design Consultant, February 2007-September 2007

- Discussed needs with prospective and established customers
- Presented possible solutions and reviewed options for customization as applicable
- Developed customer tailored presentations
- Assisted fellow consultants with presentation setup

260.402.8726

 Provided customer service throughout the sales process, including updates regarding arrival dates and follow up

# David Dale Designs Muncie, IN

Intern, May 2005-August 2005

- Assisted senior designers with design and project development
- Calculated pricing for a major project
- o Wrote specifications for two major projects
- o Assisted in the maintenance and organization of the firm's resource library

#### **EDUCATION**

Eleven Fifty Academy Carmel, IN

.NET Language Accelerated Learning Program, August 2016 Intro to Programming (JavaScript), April 2016

# Ball State University Muncie, IN

Bachelor of Science in Family and Consumer Sciences, May 2006 Concentration in Interior Design with Marketing Minor Honors Student and Recipient of Presidential Scholarship GPA: 3.986 - Graduated Summa cum Laude